天呐  对不起  你没事吧
Oh, god, I'm so sorry. Are you okay?
就算你担心我会告诉别人
You know there are easier ways to kill me,
你在法学院入学考试做过枪手  也不用这样吧
if you're worried I'll rat you out for cheating on the LSATs.
什么  别这样  瑞秋
What? Come on, Rachel.
不可理喻
Unbelievable.
瑞秋
Rachel!
瑞秋  别这样  我给你买杯新的吧
Rachel, come on, let me buy you a fresh cup.
你是真打算去买
Are you actually gonna buy it this time,
还是打算去偷呢
or are you gonna steal it?
首先  我不偷东西  我只是替考
Okay, first of all, I don't steal, I cheat.
二者截然不同  而且我已经洗手不干了
There's a big difference. And I don't do it anymore.
很有力的辩词
Oh, great defense.
对不起  法官大人  虽然我杀了她
I'm sorry, your honor, I know that I murdered her,
但我保证以后不这么做了
but I promise I won't do it anymore.
我知道你为什么生气
Look, I understand why you're mad,
但我还是觉得你对我的看法有点不公平
but I still don't think you're being entirely fair.
不公平吗
Not fair?
不公平的是你屡次替考  帮别人拿到资格证
What's not fair is that you repeatedly help people skirt a system
我却因为这个考试而当不成律师
that stands in the way of me becoming a lawyer.
别一副正气凛然的样子
You know what? Why don't you give up the whole saint act,
你之所以能发现我替考
since the only reason you figured out I was cheating
还不是因为你自己想要作弊
is 'cause you were thinkin' about cheating yourself.
想要作弊和真的作弊
Thinking about cheating and actually doing it
是两码事  别偷换概念
are two very different things, Doctor Analogy.
等等  我是错过了什么天灾吗
Whoa! Wait, did I miss an apocalypse?
人都哪去了
Where is everyone?
对于你这种记忆力超群的人
You know, for someone with a freak brain,
竟然能忘了这么重要的事情
you manage to forget everything important.
跟我来  但是别跟我说话
Follow me, but don't talk to me.
不错  哈维
Not bad, Harvey.
布拉格酒店  盈利不到三年
The Prague hotel, in the black in less than three years,
首次公开募股就很成功
and a successful I.P.O.
谁说热情不是生产力
Who said passion wasn't productive?
怎么可能有人那么说呢
I don't know anyone that's ever said that.
琼斯  我有事问你
Jones, tell me something.
你在12个国家有30家酒店
You have 30 hotels in 12 different countries,
为什么你上周却一直待在
but you spent last week
丹尼尔・维加的里斯本度假村
in Daniel Vega's Lisbon Resort.
怎么了  就是去摸摸对手的底
What? Just, you know, checkin' out the competition.
这可不止是去看看情况吧
That was more than a fact-finding mission.
你在考虑并购
You're thinking merger.
你真的觉得我对你
Do you honestly believe that I'd do that
还会先斩后奏吗
without talking to you first?
-我知道你会的  -也许我已经这么干了
- I know you would. - Then perhaps I did.
琼斯  如果你想要并购
Jones, if you try to pursue a merger,
那你对于自己苦心经营的产业
you may not control what happens to your business
就没有那么多控制权了
that you built so passionately.
好吧  侦探先生  你听我说
Okay, Sherlock, hear me out.
合并后我们就在23个国家有100百家酒店
Combined, we're 100 hotels in 23 countries.
我喜欢多几个地方落脚
I like having multiple homes.
但你不需要另一个人跟你一起还贷款
But you don't need another name on the mortgage.
这是桩不错的买卖
It's a good deal.
是啊  而我的职责是帮你谈桩更好的买卖
Yeah, and it's my job to get you a better one, okay?
答应我先不要达成协议
Promise me you didn't do a handshake deal.
唐娜
Donna!
2011年模拟庭审现在开始
Who's ready for mock trial 2011?
就像假装的庭审吗
What, like make-believe trials?
我们接下来是不是要玩大富翁了
We gonna play Monopoly after?
这就相当于是你的社交新人舞会
This is your debutante ball.
你给合伙人的第一印象很重要
The impression you make on the partners will last.
让我猜猜  哈维当初...
And let me guess, Harvey was--
传奇人物啊
Oh, legendary.
太惊讶了
Shocking.
西德尼・汤普森曾是兰德斯全球联盟的顾问
Sydney Thompson was a consultant with Lunders Global Initiative.
她喝得有点高
She had a few too many,
决定用模仿她老板的方式
and decided to entertain her friends
来娱乐下她的朋友们
with an impersonation of her boss,
她老板是莉娜・兰德斯
Lena Lunders.
这次模仿被拍了下来
This impersonation was recorded
而且上传到了社交网站
and uploaded onto a social networking site.
第二天  她就被解雇了
The next day she was fired.
西德尼现在要起诉公司不正当解雇
Sydney is now suing for wrongful termination.
我们很期待看到你们在压力下的表现
We are looking to see how you do under pressure.
这次你可没法作弊了
Can't cheat your way out of this one.
规则规定  合伙人只有在紧急情况下
The partners have been instructed to only use the associates
才能使用助理律师
in emergency situations.
游戏开始吧
Let the games begin.
好啦  叫到你名字时
All right. When your name is called,
请上前来认识下你的对手
please step up and meet your match.
你是说我的跟班吧  路易
I think you mean my bitch, Louis.
金・卡普兰
Gene Kaplan.
我很高兴杰西卡终于挑了个强势女性的案子
I'm glad Jessica finally chose a case with a strong female character.
去年我被迫要扮演交警
Last year I was forced to play a traffic cop.
乔瑟琳・劳恩斯坦
Jocelyn Lowenstein.
太浪费我的才能了
It was a total waste of my talent.
等等  你扮演了证人吗
Wait a minute, you play witnesses?
我不是扮演
Oh, I don't play anything.
我就是她的化身
I embody.
如果我跟你一队  你赢定了
And if I'm on your team, you're a winner.
-这样的话...  -不行
- Well, in that case-- - No.
好吧
Okay.
迈克・罗斯
Mike Ross.
凯尔是原告律师
Kyle for the plaintiff.
罗斯是辩护律师
Ross for the defendant.
强者必胜
May the best man win.
顺便说下  凯尔
Oh, by the way, Kyle,
你是不是全国模拟庭审冠军来着
weren't you, uh, National Mock Trial champion?
是啊  路易  从高中
That's right, Louis. In high school,
到大学  再到法学院  战无不胜
college, and law school.
本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
翻译：暮羽 马蒂 米苏 草草 跳跳糖 费列罗西瓜 圆圆
时间轴：小怡子 潘叔
■
校对：饿得慌  桃乐
后期：飞飞    总监：丢丢
■
诉 讼 双 雄
第一季  第七集
我要一份对所有维加的酒店的评估
I need an assessment of all of Vega's hotels, okay?
我需要你去查下年收入
I want you to check annual earnings,
固定资产价值
property value.
-你应该写下来  -好的
- There should be writing. - Yeah.
这些听着不像是什么紧急情况
This all doesn't sound like an emergency.
模拟审判...  好吧
The mock trial-- Okay.
我这就去
I'm on it.
-对了  哈维  -我不会给你提建议
- Uh, listen, Harvey, about-- - I don't give advice.
好吧  求你了  老师
Okay, please, sensei?
我不太清楚这个事情
I'm out of my league with this thing.
听我说
Listen to me.
不要参加庭审
Don't go to trial.
这是次模拟庭审
It's a mock trial.
我觉得参加庭审算是先决条件吧
I think the trial part is kind of a prerequisite.
听着  法律讲究的是控制
All right. Law is about control, okay?
而你对于陪审团  法官  证人
You can only control so much with a jury, judge,
和有自我情节的对方律师的控制是有限的
witnesses, and another lawyer with an ego complex.
如果那律师没有自我情节呢
What if the lawyer doesn't have an ego complex?
每个律师都有自我情节
Every lawyer has an ego complex.
公司准备的这个练习
The firm has presented an exercise
有失败的可能性
where there's potential for failure, okay?
我的意思是  尝试去创造一个情景
All I'm saying is try and create a situation
让自己立于不败之地
where that's not even a possibility.
小林丸
Kobayashi Maru.
星际迷航里星际学院的一项"考试"
小...  什么东西
Koba--what now?
星际迷航  科克舰长
Star Trek. Captain Kirk.
他修改了规章制度得以反败为胜
He wins a no-win situation by rewriting the rules.
原来你爱看《星际迷航》啊
You're a trekkie.
柯克船长是我的偶像
Hey, captain Kirk is the man,
没人能破坏他在我心中的形象
Okay? I don't wanna hear another word about it.
行了  你那个模拟庭审的问题到此为止
Now, enough with your fake law problem.
我有正经案子要处理
Let's deal with my real one.
是  船长
Aye, captain.
你知道怎么做交叉询问吗
You wanna know how to do a cross?
有些人喜欢说大话
Some people like to use big words.
有些人爱打同情牌
Some people like to go for sympathy.
但就我个人而言
But personally,
我更喜欢直击要害
I'm a little more go for the groin.
迈克
Hey, Mike.
先让你的小帮派解散吧
You mind dismissing the peanut gallery
我有些话要对你说  凯尔
so we can talk, Kyle?
抱歉  各位
I'm sorry, guys.
看样子罗斯来求饶了
Looks like Ross here came to plead for mercy.
如果你是想来和我交换人证物证的话
If you're here for the witness/exhibit exchange.
那就免了
Don't bother.
我已经知道你的人证是谁
I already know who you're gonna call
还有你会用到哪些物证
and what evidence you're gonna use.
其实  我不打算让任何证人出庭
Actually, I'm not gonna call any witnesses
也不想提交任何物证  我们和解吧
or present any evidence. Let's settle.
我赢定了
Or I can beat you.
证据已经显示原告对我的委托人
The plaintiff has shown a pattern of making
作出了一系列的诋毁性供述
derogatory statements about my client.
-道听途说  -这都在邮件里写着呢
- Hearsay. - Not the emails.
在邮件里就说明不是亲耳听到的
Which have no tone of voice
还会造成理解障碍
and are subject to interpretation.
所以你的论据是站不住脚的
Which is exactly why your argument is shaky at best.
-那就在法庭上打赢我吧  -凯尔
- Then beat me in court. - Kyle.
哈维选我当他的助理是有原因的
There's a reason that Harvey chose me to be his guy.
想知道为什么吗
Do you really wanna find out what that reason is?
我怎么知道你不是在耍花招呢
And how do I know this isn't some sort of trick?
这不是花招
It's not a trick.
这是我们大显身手的机会
This is our chance to stand out.
听着  如果和解的话
Look, settling gets us in and out of there
我们5分钟就能结案
in five minutes.
如果你撤诉  我们就可以利用剩下的时间
You drop the suit, and you and I spend the rest of the week
给合伙人们留下个深刻的印象
making ourselves indispensable to the partners
这时其他人还沉浸在模拟庭审的美梦里呢
while everyone else buries their heads in Candyland Court.
那我就违背自己的判断
I'm going against my better judgment
相信你一回
and trusting you.
那就这么说定了
So we have a deal.
丹尼尔  文书工作做得不错
Daniel, paperwork looks good,
但你俩不准备请律师  这可不太好
despite the fact that you two decided to go lawyer commando.
细节决定成败啊
The devil's always in the details.
哈维  我知道仓促行事不是你的风格
Harvey, I know that impulse purchases don't exist in your world,
但现在时机到了
but the timing was right.
说到细节
And as for the details,
还是交给我的个人律师斯科特吧
I'd like to leave that to my man Scott.
他经常迟到吗
Does he always like to be late?
是"她"
She.
刚从伦敦飞过来
Just got off a plane from London.
来见一下达娜・斯科特
Meet Ms. Dana Scott.
欢迎
Welcome.
-你好  谢谢  -斯科特
- Hi. Thank you. - Scottie.
-哈维  -你们原来认识啊
- Harvey. - Oh, you two know each other!
我们是哈佛法学院的同学
We went to harvard law together.
哈维当时是班上第五名  而我是...
Harvey was fifth in the class, and I was--
我忘了  我是第几来着
Oh, I forget. What was it?
你那时嫁给图书馆了吧
Married to the library?
没错  我是第一名
That's right. Number one.
学习方面你确实是第一
Number one at studying.
好了  这边请
Okay, this way.
告诉我  斯科特
Tell me, Scottie,
当我们真正对峙公堂时
What's my success rate against you in the real world
我对你的胜率是多少
where we practice real law?
哈维  在并购案里不存在谁赢谁输
Harvey, there should be no winners or losers in a merger.
皆大欢喜
Just a happy new couple.
3比0  胜负一目了然
That's right, 3 and 0.
我们还是让他们谈谈公事
Well, I say we let these two talk deal points
我也去尝一尝你酒店主厨的拿手海鲈
While I try your chef's famous sea bass.
必须的  友谊第一
Absolutely. Play nice.
我们喜欢对方  但显然你们两个不是
We like each other, even if you two don't.
嫁给了图书馆
"Married to the library"?
又不是我的错
It's not my fault.
图书馆都是你能找到最好的了
Library was the best you could do.
你做好初步建议书了吗
Do you have the preliminary proposal?
没呢  我刚从伦敦飞过来
No, I just flew in from London
毫无准备
completely unprepared.
别被吓到  我的用词比较晦涩
Try not to be intimidated. I use some big words.
"过度补偿"可算不上晦涩
Overcompensation isn't that big of a word.
不算吗
It isn't?
我很想见识下资深合伙人的水平
I can hardly wait to see the work of a senior partner.
看来我升职一事已经出现在
I see my promotion popped up
你的哈维・斯佩克特谷歌快讯上了
on your Harvey Specter Google Alert.
出现在我脑海里的可不止这一件事
That's not all that's going to pop up.
我们很久没在床上做了
Can't remember the last time we had a bed.
合作酒店并购案  这绝对是近水楼台
Pretty convenient that we're working on a hotel merger.
还记得那个采矿案吗
Remember the mining deal?
27号矿井那个案子吗  我怎么忘得了
Shaft 27? How could I forget?
听着  关于尽职审查...
Listen, about the due diligence--
哈维
Ah, Harvey.
你知道规矩的
You know the rules.
在完事前别跟我谈案子的事
No case negotiations till we're done.
我想那得有一会了
I think that might be a while.
忍不住想看我的精彩表现吧
Couldn't resist seeing brilliance in action, huh?
实际上  我必须出席
Actually, I have to be here.
我要扮演原告之一
I'm playing the part of the plaintiff.
我知道你很生气
Wow. I knew you were pissed,
但没想到你这么小心眼
but I didn't realize you were petty.
-什么意思  -是个形容词
- What does that mean? - It's an adjective.
意思是心胸狭隘又恶毒
It means small-minded and spiteful.
你居然帮我的对手
You chose to work with the one guy who's going against me.
凯尔征求我意见  我同意了
Kyle asked me, and I said yes.
算了
You know what?
无所谓  反正你也没机会出庭作证
It doesn't really matter,'cause you're never gonna take the stand.
是吗  为什么
Really? How's that?
等着瞧吧
It's a surprise.
准备期待模拟庭审传奇的诞生吧
But prepare to watch a mock trial legend be born.
律师们都准备好各自的开场陈述了吗
Is counsel ready to proceed with opening statements?
我们打算提交一份调解协议
We'd like to submit a settlement agreement--
原告律师准备就绪  法官大人
The plaintiff is ready, your honor.
到底谁说了算  律师
Which is it, counselor?
原告律师和我
The counsel for the plaintiff
昨天达成调解共识
and I agreed to a settlement yesterday.
他肯定是误会了  我们是讨论过
He must've misunderstood. We had discussed,
但并没达成共识
but I never agreed to anything.
你们签了协议吗
Do you have a signed agreement?
没有
No.
那我们准备开始模拟庭审吧
Then we are ready to proceed.
由你先开始
You have the floor.
谢谢
Thank you.
2010年3月31日
On March 31, 2010,
西德尼・汤普森对于自己电话被录音一事
Sydney Thompson was unwittingly recorded
毫不知情
on a cell phone.
她开了个玩笑
She made a joke,
我相信法庭里的每个人
the type of joke that I'm sure every person in this courtroom
都曾开过这样的玩笑
has made at one point or another...
罗斯先生
Mr. Ross.
Mr. Ross!
你准备好了吗
Are you ready?
被告方
Um, the, uh, the defense...
根据波马斯特状告怀特里一案的结果
According to Bowmaster V. Whitely,
如果一方当事人
if the party to a settlement is surprised
突然得知和解被拒
by the repudiation of the settlement,
那么法庭必须给出合理时限
then the court must provide a reasonable amount of time
让其做好庭审准备
to prepare for the trial.
-合理时限  -是的  法官大人
- Reasonable time. - Yes, your honor.
给你五分钟
You get five minutes.
维加不止这些资产
Vega has more property.
迪贝克更有潜力
Debeque has more potential.
潜力很难用金钱来衡量
Which is harder to monetarily define.
这不是图书馆  斯科特
This isn't a library, Scottie.
我的客户不懂并购
My guy's an up-and-comer.
所以你的客户才会想搞突袭
That's why your guy's pouncing.
你的委托人是位冲动型购物者
Your client is an impulse shopper,
这就导致他成功得快
which is what may have made him a quick success,
但失败得也快
but it could make him an even faster failure.
他是个充满激情的人
So he's a passionate guy.
他每爱上一座城市  就在那里建一座酒店
He falls in love with a city, and he builds himself a hotel.
你凭什么对他的业绩提出质疑呢
Who are you to argue with his track record?
我是现实主义者
I'm a realist,
我从没见过哪个项目能谈得这么快
and I have never seen a deal pushed through so quickly.
那又怎样
So what?
也许你的客户明早一觉醒来
So your guy might wake up tomorrow
就反悔不想谈了
and decide that he doesn't wanna do this,
所以在没有签好协议前
which is why I'm not showing you
我不会给你看我们的内部账簿
our private books without a signed deal.
-是开玩笑吗  -我在笑吗
- Is that a joke? - Am I laughing?
虽然在并购培训班  我总是打瞌睡...
Look, I may not have been awake during our M&A clinic--
除了你抄我笔记的时候
Except for when you were copying my notes.
没那么简单  你写字速度像超人
Which was no walk in the park. You wrote like a monkey.
不管怎样  尽职审查是必须的
But in any case, due diligence is a requirement.
我对我的委托人有义务
I have an obligation to my client.
那我们没法达成协议了
Then we don't have a deal.
大家都会知道是你否了这个协议
And everyone's gonna know it's because you killed it.
知道吗...
You know...
看来你并不急着把你们的内部账簿给我们看
I don't see you rushing to show us your private books.
我没什么好隐瞒的
I have nothing to hide.
你现在完全可以看我们的账簿
You can have full access to our books right now.
很好  你给我看你们的  我给你看我们的
Great. You show me yours, and I'll show you mine.
别说出来  哈维
Don't say it, Harvey.
迈克
Mike.
-你没事吧  -现在你关心我了
- Hey, are you okay? - Now you care?
罗斯先生  我要警告你
Mr. Ross, I'm gonna have to ask you
不能和我的委托人说话
not to speak to my client.
她不是你的委托人
She's not your client.
她是律师助理瑞秋
She is Rachel the paralegal.
我只有五分钟准备  你最好赶紧从我面前消失
And I only have five minutes, so you should really get out of my face.
-你有什么问题吗  迈克  -我的问题是
- What's your problem, Mike? - My problem is that
你没胆量来一场公平的较量  凯尔
you don't have the balls to make this a fair fight, Kyle.
律师这行就没有公平竞争之说
Lawyering isn't about fighting fair,
你最好不要诬告陷害
and you'd better watch your false accusations,
否则我要告你诽谤
or I might just sue you for defamation.
跟我来
Come on.
被告方想要反诉
The defendant wishes to countersue.
反诉:简单地说就是在民事诉讼中  被告反告原告
理由呢
On what grounds?
我觉得那是我该说的话  律师
I believe that's my line, counselor.
毁损名誉
Defamation of character.
原告的录像给莉娜・兰德斯
The plaintiff's video negatively impacted
带来了极其负面的影响
the perception of Lena Lunders
也严重减损了其财政收入
and impaired her financial well-being.
那太荒唐了  法官大人
That's ridiculous, your honor.
为了诽谤中伤我的委托人
In order for there to be defamation,
证据录像可能是伪造出来的
the statements made would've been false.
这和本案无关
That's not the case here.
那么你应该可以在法庭上给出相应的证明
Then you should have no problem proving that in court.
反诉成立
The countersuit is allowed.
你是认真的吗
Are you serious?
你是不是想要到法官席前
Would you like to approach the bench
看看我到底有多认真
and find out how serious I am?
法官大人  被告方应该在开庭前
Your honor, the defense should've filed counterclaims
上交反诉材料
before the trial began.
是的  应该是这样
Yes, he should have.
但这么多助理中  没人有这种远见
But no one in this crop of associates had the foresight to do so.
我们起草了完整的案情附录
And we drafted a whole addendum
以免你们有人提出反诉
just because we assumed one of you would.
所以我批准该请求
So I'm going to allow it.
你对此有意见吗
Do you have a problem with that?
没有  法官大人
No, your honor.
现在改为诽谤案审理
This is now a defamation trial.
准备时间到周五
You have until Friday to prepare.
漂亮的反击  反应很敏捷
Nice recovery. Thinking on your feet.
要不是你太天真  也不用如此了
But you wouldn't have had to if you hadn't been so naive.
谢谢  法官大人
Thank you, your honor.
谈判怎么样
How'd the negotiation go?
你占上风了吗
You come out on top?
为什么你没告诉我斯科特是对方律师
Why didn't you tell me Scottie was opposing counsel?
因为我不希望你怯场
Because I didn't want you to have performance anxiety.
作为律师  她很强势
About the case. She's tough.
-你太无聊了  -你大门没关
- You're obvious. - And your fly's unzipped.
-骗人  -之前是的
- No, it isn't. - But it was earlier today.
你可以做得更好的
You can do better.
斯科特在床上这么说的吗
Ooh, is that what Scottie said?
把合同要点打出来
Type up the deal points.
她让步了  迪贝克会主导大局
I got her to cave. Debeque's gonna run the show.
我不过是给她看了我们的账簿
All I had to do was show her our books.
我真服了
I can't believe it.
你教我的那招把我害惨了
You gave me, like, the worst advice anyone's ever given another person.
戏就演到这儿吧  朱丽叶
Take the drama down a notch, Juliet.
我想要和解  但却彻底被暗算了
I tried to settle, and I got completely blindsided.
我让你和解  没让你扮傻
I told you to settle. I didn't tell you to be stupid.
现实中的庭审可没这么简单
What do you think's gonna happen in the real world?
你要未雨绸缪
You have to be prepared for anything.
但在现实中
Well, in the real world,
我起码不用找人假扮证人
I won't have to be looking for someone to play
来参加我的假冒审判
my fake witness in my fake trial.
等下  你想什么呢
Wait, wait, wait. What do you think?
你以为证人会自己跳出来作证吗
Do you think witnesses are just gonna jump up and present themselves?
不会
'Cause they're not.
有时  即使你有证人
And sometimes when you have one,
他们也可能会消失或放弃
they disappear or recant.
这些情况你都要学会处理
And you know what you do? You deal with it.
模拟庭审旨在明确你想要成为哪类律师
Mock trial is about figuring out what type of lawyer you wanna be,
而律师只有两类  胜者和败者
and there's only two types-- winners and losers.
听起来不错  哈维  但是我没做好准备
That sounds great, Harvey, but I haven't prepared.
我找不到人扮演我的委托人或证人
I don't have anyone to play my client or my witness,
而对方律师又是我不信任的人
and apparently I'm going up against someone that I can't trust.
不管怎样  想办法打败他
Figure out a way to beat him anyway.
对方遵守了规则时  胜者不会去找借口
Winners don't make excuses when the other side plays the game.
唐娜  我校对了酒店合并的最终协议
Hey, Donna, I proofed that final agreement on the hotel merger.
问个问题  哈维会不会用拼写检查啊
Quick question -- has Harvey ever heard of spell-check?
我的天
Oh, my god.
-对不起  -你...
- Sorry. - Are you--
没事  没事  不要紧的  给你
No, no, no. It's okay. Here.
没事  没事  你不用说话
No, no, no. You don't have to talk.
嘘嘘  没事了
Shh, shh, shh. It's okay.
没事的  他有时说的话
It's okay. He says things sometimes,
确实...确实很伤人
and they--and they cut to the bone.
他对我也那样  我懂的  你就...
He does it to me too. I know, so...
不赖吧
It's not bad, right?
我还能像黛咪・摩尔那样单眼流泪
I can also do the Demi Moore single tear--
凡是为了剧情需要  左右眼都可以
left eye or right eye-- if that's better for the character.
好吧  你吓到我了  怎么回事啊
Okay, I'm scared. What's going on?
要为你扮演莉娜・兰德斯
If I'm gonna play Lena Lunders for you,
我得能调动我的全部感情啊
I need to be able to use my full range of emotions.
我的天  爱死你了
Oh, my god. I love you.
是啊  我知道
Yeah, I know.
精神集中
Focus.
你还需要一个证人  到了这时候
You need another witness, and at this point,
公司里其他的人都被预定了
everybody else in the firm is booked up.
来找妈妈给你擦屁股了  罗斯
Aw! Is mommy helping you clean up your mess, Ross?
你说谁是妈呢
Am I mommy in this scenario?
什么
What? Uh...
我是说  罗斯是个...小屁孩
Ross is just... a baby.
我的天
Oh, my god.
-真不敢相信我要输给那个二货  -得了
- I cannot believe I'm gonna lose to that tool. - Okay, come on.
少卖可怜了  去外面再找个证人来
No pity parties. Go to an outside source for the other witness.
被告的朋友  你得找个漂亮的
For the best friend you need somebody pretty,
有同情心的  最重要的是
sympathetic, and most importantly,
愿意为你两肋插刀
willing to go above and beyond for you.
你来干嘛
What are you doing here?
珍妮  别这样  我需要你的帮助
Jenny, come on, I need your help.
我没别处可去了
Got nowhere else to go.
你吼我  吻我  推开我  然后消失
You yelled at me. Kissed me. Pushed me away. Disappeared.
我们很久没说话了
I haven't talked to you in forever.
我都不知道你最近在干嘛
I don't even know what's going on in your life.
你要是放我进去  我就说给你听
Well, if you let me in, I'll explain,
我保证这故事很精彩
and I promise it's a really good story.
就是说你一直生活在谎言当中
So you've been living a lie this whole time.
对
Yeah.
太帅了
That's awesome.
-真的吗  -对啊
- Really? - Yeah!
我是说  就双重生活而言
I mean, as far as double lives go,
你大概比不过克拉克・肯特  但也不错了
you're maybe not as cool as Clark Kent, but still.
克拉克・肯特把内裤穿在外面就成了超人
克拉克・肯特
Clark Kent?
行了  你不能再吃了
Okay, you're cut off.
-怎么了  -没事
- What? - Nothing.
能告诉你  感觉真好
It just feels really good to tell you.
我都找不到倾诉对象
I don't really have anybody I can talk to about it.
你信任我嘛
You trust me.
是啊  我想是吧
Yeah. I guess I do.
那样真好
I like that.
不过这个更好
Ooh, but I really like this.
不得不说  哈维
Gotta hand it to you, Harvey.
你虽然不能跟一个女人长相厮守
You may not be able to commit to a woman,
却在这房子里住了很久
but you have been in this place a very long time.
-它懂我  -又没什么需求
- She gets me. - And has no needs.
我想你不知道这里的维护费多高吧
I don't think you understand how high maintenance this place is.
他同意了你的全部条件
He agreed to all your terms...
虽然我抗议说  他本可拿到更多
despite my protest that he could do better.
-那我们完成任务了  -就差几个签名了
- So we're done. - Minus a few signatures.
-那就是没完成  -要我走吗
- That's not done. - Want me to leave?
陪审团各位成员  请注意...
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury, please note--
能问个问题吗
Can I ask a question?
不  作为证人  你不能提问
No, you can't ask questions as a witness.
不要提问
Don't ask questions.
-陪审团各位成员...  -好吧  我懂了
- Ladies and gentlemen, please-- - Yeah, okay, I know that.
可你在干嘛啊
But, um, what are you doing?
-什么意思  -你走来走去
- What do you mean? - You're walking around
一副不可一世的样子
like you have a giant stick up your ass.
珍妮  这是庭审
It's a trial, Jenny.
我得表现得强势一点
I have to be powerful.
-可那不是你的本性  -多谢夸奖
- But that's not you. - Thanks.
我是说  你很有魅力  又幽默
No, you are charming, and funny,
值得信任  那才是你的强项
and trustworthy. That's your power.
我想混进法学院入学考试时  那是优点
And that's great when I'm trying to con my way into the LSATs,
但这是法庭啊
but this is a courtroom.
-在这儿不顶用的  -可你的本性没变
- It's useless there. - But it's still you.
那要怎样
So?
深吸一口气
Take a deep breath.
好吧
Okay.
跟我聊聊
Just talk to me.
问我在哪上班
Ask me where do I work.
-你在哪上班  -兰德斯全球联盟
- Where do you work? - Lunders Global Initiative.
问我怎么认识西德尼的
Ask me how I know Sydney.
你怎么认识西德尼的
How do you know Sydney?
她曾是我的朋友
She was my friend.
自从她走之后  我一直很想她
And I've missed her every day that she's been gone.
你们为什么断交了
And why aren't you friends anymore?
我不知道
I don't know.
如果你庭审这样表现
If you do it like that...
他们会爱上你的
they'll fall in love with you.
你能把这件脱下来吗  脱掉
Would you take this off? Take it off.
脱啊
Take it...
斯科特  你太棒了
Scottie, that was amazing.
注意啦  哈维
Careful, Harvey.
你得补水
You need to hydrate.
你刚跑了个马拉松
You just ran a marathon.
我觉得你刚刚击败我了
And I think you just beat me.
你怎么一脸律师的神情
That's a lawyer look.
上法学院时
Law school.
模拟审判结束后  在图书馆里
Post-mock trial in the library.
在第二联邦上诉法院
2nd circuit court of appeals.
集体诉讼案期间  在准备室的桌子上
Class action on the prep room table.
邓普斯和解案  在我办公室里
Dempsey settlement, in my office,
在桌上桌下都做过
On the desk and under.
干嘛呢  亮点总结啊
So what are we doing? Um, a highlight reel?
没错啊  那些都是最具亮点时刻  对不
As a matter of fact, we are. Those were top moments, right?
-确实不赖  -不止是不赖  是棒极了
- They weren't bad. - No, they were great.
而我刚刚意识到这次要比那几次还亮
And I just realized this was better.
你刚才是达到了最高境界
You were the best you've ever been,
-而我也知道为什么  -为什么
- and I know why. - Why?
谈判时你对我有所隐瞒
You hid something from me in the negotiation,
我要知道你瞒了什么
and I wanna know what.
你知道吗  你的猜测太荒唐了
You know what? You are ridiculous.
别假装你什么都不知道  好吗
Oh, you know what? Don't do that, okay?
-知道什么  -你以为我不知道
- Do what? - You think I don't know
-这是一场胜利的欢爱吗  -什么
- victory sex when I see it, huh? - See it?
到底是怎么回事
What is it?
是不是维加哪里的产业要垮了
Was it one of Vega's properties is bankrupt?
是布宜诺斯艾利斯那边吗
The Buenos Aires one?
你还指望我说什么呢  哈维
Wh-wh-what do you want me to say, Harvey?
没错  你猜对了 你上了我的套
Yes, you got me! I screwed you.
-怎么回事  -天哪
-How? - Oh, my God.
你想现在听我解析吗
You want an anatomy lesson now?
那是我的衬衫
That's my shirt.
把它看作我打败你的奖赏吧
Consider it a winner's reward.
哈维
Hey, Harvey.
你想得没错
You were right.
在过去二十四小时里
There's been a steady stream of stock buying
维加的公司一直在收购我们的股票
by Vega's company in the last 24 hours.
这是敌意收购
It's a hostile takeover.
没错  但他们为什么要打合并的幌子呢
Yeah, but why are they disguising it as a merger?
他们想拿到我们的内部账簿
They wanted access to our private books.
-她耍了我一把  -什么
- She tricked me. - What?
她假装不愿意交出他们的账簿
She pretended she didn't wanna hand over their books
这样她要我们的账簿时  我就不会留意
so I wouldn't notice when she asked for ours.
这是个老套的伎俩了
It's a classic maneuver.
-她让我以为这是我的主意  -你怎么知道的
- She made me think it was my idea. - How do you know that?
因为这招是我教她的
'Cause I taught her how to do it.
现在他们知道迪贝克的公司实力有多强
So now they see how strong Debeque's company is,
所以想要收购
and they wanna buy it.
而且他们会在斯科特回伦敦之前就开始运营
And they'll be running it by the time Scottie's back in London.
哇  我才离开你两天  就出了篓子
Wow. I leave you alone for two days...
对  这次是我的错
Yeah, this is my mistake.
这就像哈雷彗星一样罕见
This is Halley's comet.
仔细看吧  因为不会再有下次了
Take a good look, 'cause it won't happen again.
那你打算怎么办
So what are you gonna do?
我想知道迪贝克最值钱的酒店有哪些
I wanna know which of Debeque's hotels are the most valuable
还有我们最快要多久才能让它们上市
and how fast we can get them on the market.
等等  你想让迪贝克卖掉他最好的酒店吗
Wait, you want Debeque to sell his best hotels?
这叫做弃车保帅
It's called the crown jewel defense.
我们放弃最值钱的资产
We unload the highest grossing assets,
这会让别人对他的公司失去兴趣
and we make ourselves look undesirable.
迪贝克绝对不会同意的
Debeque'll never agree to that.
相信我  迪贝克对他的公司倾注了巨大的心血
Trust me. Debeque has enough passion for his company
为了保全大局  他不会计较这点得失
that he'll be willing to chop off an arm to save the body.
好吧
Okay.
你过目不忘  是吧
You know you had that memorized the first time you read it, right?
是啊  但我还没过目完呢
Yeah, but I didn't finish reading it
因为有个证人在我眼前晃来晃去
because a certain witness chose to be distracting.
那还真是难为你了
That must've been rough for you.
是啊  很纠结
Yeah, you have no idea.
哪儿有水
Where can I get some water?
我怕等会儿嗓子会哑
I need to make sure my voice holds up.
就在那边
Right there.
我们来订个协议
I'll make you a deal.
赢了的可以得到那个妞
The winner gets the girl.
我可不想再跟你订什么协议了
You know, I'm never gonna make another deal with you again.
-是吗  为什么
- No? - Why not?
-你是不是要迟到了  -没错
- Aren't you late for... - Oh, I am.
他们让我想起了少不更事的你和我
They remind me of a younger, less attractive you and me.
拜托别说这种话
Please don't say things like that.
我知道你在操纵赌局
And I know that you rigged the lottery
好让迈克遭受凯尔的蹂躏
so that Mike would get Kyle.
操纵也好  推动也好  只是说法不同
Please. Rigged, expedited, they're all just words.
况且  你不想看你的小朋友如何表现吗
Besides, don't you wanna see what your boy is made of?
你是想让我也下注吗
You talking bet?
-没错  -赌金跟以前一样
- Yeah. - Usual amount.
那就这么定了
I believe we have a wager.
你知道吗  有些人洗过澡才会来上班
Well, you know what? Some of us shower before we go to work.
-斯佩克特先生  -省省吧
- Mr. Specter-- - You know what? Save it.
好吧
Right.
你感觉如何
How you feeling?
-很好  -很好
-Good. - Good?
-没错  -那就好
- Yeah. - Good.
上庭作证之前吃安定
Is it inappropriate to take a xanax
是不是不太好呢
if you're a witness in a trial?
我见过有些委托人做得更过分
I've seen clients do much worse.
其实  我不是委托人
Actually, I'm not a client.
我是来为我朋友的模拟庭审做证人的
I'm a witness in a friend's mock trial.
记住一点  如果进展不顺利
One thing-- if you get into trouble,
就不要再针对案情  要针对人
don't play the case. Play the man.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
好律师会去研究事实
Good lawyers worry about facts.
而伟大的律师则研究对手
Great lawyers worry about their opponents.
凯尔骄傲自大  手段奸猾
Kyle is cocky and devious.
想办法利用这点打败他
Figure out a way to use that against him.
明白  还有吗
Okay. Anything else?
狠狠地教训他一顿
Kick his ass.
-你的朋友是谁  -迈克・罗斯
- Who's your friend? - Oh, uh, Mike Ross.
你认识他吗
Do you know him?
算是吧  虽然公司很大
Uh, yeah. Uh, it's a big firm,
但我知道他是谁
but I know who he is.
是吧
Yeah.
天啊  我不知道我怎么这么紧张
God, I don't know why I'm so nervous.
我知道这对他很重要
I just know this is a big deal to him,
我不想让他失望
and I don't wanna let him down.
西德尼・汤普森在一个聚会上开了个玩笑
Sydney Thompson was at a party and made a joke.
她并无恶意  也没想到会被信以为真
It wasn't meant to be mean or to be taken as fact,
更不希望将其公开
and it most certainly was never meant to be public.
辩方将会证明...
The defense will show--
西德尼・汤普森明知自己的行为
That Sydney Thompson chose to publicly
会损害莉娜・兰德斯的名誉
defame her boss with an impression
及其公司的利益
that she knew would be damaging,
却依然公开诽谤了她的老板
both to Lena Lunders' reputation and her company.
我方传唤莉娜・兰德斯出庭作证
I call Lena Lunders to the stand.
呃  你要休息一下吗
Uh...do you need a minute?
不
No.
我可以继续  谢谢关心
I can continue. Thank you.
请开始吧
Please.
我是个自食其力的女人
I'm a self-made woman.
我一手建立起全球联盟
I created the Global Initiative
专门解决第三世界国家的问题
to target problems in third-world countries.
我很看重自己的事业
I take my work very seriously,
如果有人拿这个开玩笑
and if a joke can be made of that,
请便
fine.
但是作为一个身居高位的女人
But as a woman in power,
人们只看到你的成功的一面
people look at your success and label you.
他们不知道一个女人
They don't know the complexity it takes
要在这一行取得成功有多艰难
for a woman to succeed in this business.
如果有人贬低你辛苦取得的成就
And when someone undermines that,
那...
well...
我们就不得不为自己抗辩了
we have to fight for ourselves...
不是吗  法官大人
Don't we, your honor?
反对
Objection.
你是在阐述做职场女性很艰难吗
So it's hard to be a woman in business?
这和本案的事实毫无关系
That has nothing to do with the facts of this case.
要想了解你的委托人给兰德斯小姐
Well, we can only understand the damage
造成了多大损失  我们必须充分理解
your client has done by fully understanding the care
她是如何苦心树立起威信的
with which Miss Lunders has built her reputation.
对不起
Um, I'm sorry.
你能再问一遍吗
Can you ask me the question one more time?
深呼吸
Take a deep breath.
这只是你我之间的对话
It's just you and me.
谈谈你的工作  好吗
We're just gonna have a conversation about your job, okay?
好的
Yeah, okay.
你是如何认识被告西德尼・汤普森的
How do you know the defendant Sydney Thompson?
我们是同事  入司时级别相同
We were coworkers. We started at the same level,
后来我被提升为她的直属上司
and then I was promoted to be her immediate superior.
你了解视频一事吗
And do you know about the video in question?
是的  我参加了那晚的聚会
Yes. I was at the party that night.
你们那晚是在庆祝什么
And what were you celebrating that night?
庆祝我升职一事
My promotion.
同一个晚上  有意思
Same night. That's interesting.
金妮斯小姐
Miss Ginnesse.
你对模仿一事怎么看
What did you think of the impersonation?
既过分又刻薄
It was too far. It was mean.
那你认为汤普森小姐为何会那么做
So why do you think Miss Thompson did it?
兰德斯提拔了我
Miss Lunders promoted me.
西德尼很不爽
Sydney hated it.
所以她拍了那个视频
And that's why she made the video.
谢谢  金妮斯小姐
Well, thank you, Miss Ginnesse.
讯问完毕  法官大人
Nothing further, your honor.
西德尼有没有告诉你
Did Sydney ever tell you
她对你的提拔很不满
that she hated your promotion?
-不完全是这样   -请回答有还是没有
- Not exactly.  - Yes or no, please.
-没有  -那你怎么知道
- No. - Well, then how do you know
她对你的升职不满
that she hated your promotion?
我能看出来
I could just tell.
你能看出我现在在想什么吗
Can you tell what I'm thinking right now?
希望我对你所说的每一句话都毫无异议吗
That you're wishing I would agree with everything you say?
不对  我在想  如果你能读出我的想法
No. I was thinking that if you could actually read my mind,
我就不用费事问你这些问题了
I wouldn't bother asking you the questions.
但你读不出我的想法  对吗
But you can't read my mind, can you?
不能  我...我是经理...
No, I'm--I'm managing director--
不  我敢肯定你也读不出西德尼的想法
No. And I'm pretty sure you can't read Sydney's either.
所以你其实不知道她为何拍了那段视频
And you actually have no idea why she made that video.
对吗
Correct?
是的  我不知道
I guess I don't. No.
下午好  斯科特小姐
Good afternoon, Miss Scott.
谢谢
Thank you.
你是想给我个体面的告别吗
Are you here to give me a proper send-off?
在大街上不能干那种事儿吧
I don't think we can do that out here on the street.
-你确定吗  -你骗过了我
- You sure? - You tricked me.
我很佩服
I'm impressed.
公平地说  维加确实想进行合并
To be fair, Vega did want a merger.
我刚说服他
I just convinced him that,
鉴于你客户鲁莽收购的一贯做法
given your client's propensity for rash purchases,
让他继续掌权不是个好主意
that allowing him to stay in charge was a bad idea.
维加想要迪贝克的酒店  而不希望他来管理
Vega needed Debeque's hotels  minus Debeque,
我想出了一个办法
and I found a way.
你的办法不会让他满意的
One that he never asked for or wanted,
而且他也不需要你的建议了
and one that he's never gonna get.
这...这是真的吗
Was--is this for real?
迪贝克的三处房产
Three of Debeque's properties.
将于今晚上市
It'll be on the market by the end of the day.
他绝不会让你卖掉他的王牌产业的
He's never gonna let you sell off his crown jewels.
强硬的客户有一点好处
See, that's the thing about passionate clients.
一经背叛  他们会恼羞成怒
When they're crossed, they get angry,
不惜一切代价进行反击
and they'll do anything to get back.
别这样  哈维
Don't do this, Harvey.
还有一个办法
Look, there's another way we can do this.
我们把客户都约到一起
We can get our clients into a room together.
你向他们认个错
You can tell them you were wrong,
然后说服他们继续商讨合并事宜
and we can convince them back into a merger.
汤普森小姐  你拍模仿视频的目的是什么
Miss Thompson, what was the intent behind your impersonation?
我只是想搞搞笑
I was just trying to be funny.
办公室里人人都讲笑话
Everyone in our office makes jokes,
而事实上
And as a matter of fact,
兰德斯女士鼓励我们不拘礼节
Ms. Lunders encourages us to be informal.
仅凭事实  我赢不了这个案子
I can't win this just on facts.
但我预料到了
But I expected it.
我想每个人都渴望升职
I think everyone has the impulse to move up,
但某些时候  你不得不学会释然
but at a certain point, you just have to let it go.
我就是这么做的
So that's what I did.
你打算怎么做
What are you gonna do?
我从未对老板心怀恶意
I've never held ill will for my boss.
我得在这个女人身上做文章  而不是案子本身
I'm gonna play the woman, not the case.
你说你预料到自己不会被提拔  对吗
You say you expected to be passed over for a promotion, correct?
-是的  -而且你已经申请过三次了
- Yes. - And yet you applied three times?
-是的  -而你却从未被提拔
- Yes. - And you were never promoted?
如我所说  是的
As I said, yes.
而当娜拉・金妮斯升职时
And when Nora Ginnesse was promoted,
你给其他同事写了措辞刻薄的电子邮件
you wrote scathing emails to the rest
-作为回应  -不  并非刻薄
- of your coworkers in response. - No, not scathing.
我的初衷只是搞笑
The intent was to be funny.
对了  你喜欢搞笑
Oh, right, you like to be funny.
谁不喜欢笑口常开呢
Who doesn't like to laugh?
因此而名誉扫地的人不会喜欢的
Someone whose reputation has been ruined.
-反对  -个人想法而已
- Objection. - Just a thought.
-这是在自证  -反对有效
- It's testifying. - Sustained.
罗斯先生  请提问
Mr. Ross, questions.
对不起  法官大人
I'm sorry, your honor.
原谅我  我只是想搞笑
Forgive me. I was just trying to be funny.
在你的绩效评估报告上  莉娜・兰德斯写道
On your performance review, Lena Lunders wrote,
"敬业精神可嘉  缺乏工作技巧"
"Good work ethic. Lacks skills."
你觉得这样的评价公平吗
Do you think that's a fair assessment?
公平  我...我不知道
Fair? I--I don't know.
你的同事们都升职了
Well, your coworkers were promoted,
而你的老板却认为你只是个庸才
and your boss was calling you mediocre.
-你是庸才吗  -不是
- Are you mediocre? - No.
那为何你没被提拔
So why haven't you been promoted?
我不知道
I don't know.
你觉得自己有资格得到更好的待遇吗
Do you think you deserve better?
-人人都有资格吧  - 那你为何没去尝试
- Doesn't everyone? - So why haven't you tried?
-我试了  -那你为什么没有进步
- I have tried. - Why haven't you improved?
我没说过我没进步
I didn't say I haven't improved.
你的考核报告上说了
Well, your review did.
你五年以来都没升职  也证明了这点
Your five years without a promotion did.
你因为自己没被提拔而恼羞成怒
Look, you were so angry that you weren't moving forward
将怨气发泄在你老板身上...
that you lashed out at your boss--
-不  -反对  自证其罪
- No. - Objection! Testifying!
-别人都爬得比你高  -那又怎样
- Everyone was moving past you. - So what?
他们凭借能力实现了目标
People making good on their--
纠缠证人  法官大人
Badgering, your honor.
-反对有效  -他们能够有所成就
- Sustained. - People who could cut it.
我也能成功
I can cut it!
对不起  法官大人
Excuse me, your honor.
和解协议仍然有效
Settlement's still on the table.
-什么  -我们和解吧
- What? - Let's settle.
同样的条件  双赢
Same deal. Win-win.
-不  我不和解  -你说什么
- No, I'm good. - Excuse me?
我知道那表情是什么意思  罗斯
I've seen the moony looks, Ross.
你喜欢她
You like her,
所以你给我提供了一个和解方案
so you're offering me a settlement
因为你不想伤害她
because you don't want to hurt her feelings.
但是我宁愿看到你伤害她
But I'd rather see if you'll break her.
醒醒吧  兄弟
Giddy-up, cowboy.
律师
Counselor.
还要继续问吗
Would you like to proceed?
我问完了  法官大人
No, your honor.
-你确定吗  -是的  法官大人
- Are you sure? - Yes, your honor.
没有问题了
Nothing further.
正常情况下我们要开始结案陈词了
Well, normally we'd move on to closing statements,
但这一周大家都很疲惫
but it's been a long week,
而且我们都知道结果是什么了
and honestly, we all know where this is going.
所以法庭判决被告获胜
So court rules in favor of the defendant.
休庭
This court is adjourned.
罗斯先生
Mr. Ross.
天真  心软
Naive and soft.
不是皮尔逊・哈德曼律所提倡的品质
Not qualities we're looking for at Pearson Hardman.
先生们  我很感激你们能心平气和坐下来谈谈
Gentlemen, I appreciate you leaving the swords at home.
我们从一个纯粹的合并案开始
What started off as a true merger
并不希望搞出别的事情来
never needed to become anything different.
丹尼尔  我希望你听我说
Daniel, I want you to listen to me.
我了解哈维  他只想和你的公司合并
I know Harvey, and he just wants to merge your businesses
这样他的时薪就能加倍了
so he can double his billable hours.
行了  斯科特
Quiet, Scott.
我想听听他要说什么
I wanna hear what he has to say.
我过来是替我的客户达成他想要的交易
I'm just here to get my client the deal that he wants,
他要的就是合并  不是吗  琼斯
and what he wants is a merger, is that right, Jones?
没错
That's right.
丹尼尔 你的律所已经走到了
Daniel. Your law firm overreached in a situation
进退两难的境地
where it wasn't necessary.
并不完全是斯科特的错
It's not entirely Scottie's fault.
好胜是律师的天性
We lawyers all have an instinct to win,
但是有时候我们可能
but sometimes we may
不能完全理解这意味着什么
not fully understand what that means.
我们知道这意味着什么
We understand what it means.
也许你知道  也许你不知道
Well, maybe you do, and maybe you don't.
对我而言
For me,
这意味着两位男士谈回到最初的协议
it would be to see both men return to the initial deal
使双方的生意达成共赢
so that you can grow both your businesses,
而不是一个公司声誉扫地
instead of having one company with a hostile reputation
而另一家像以前一样变成空壳
and the other a shell of what it once was.
对我来说  那可算不上是胜利
I mean, that doesn't sound like a win to me.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我们继续谈最初的那个协议吧
Let's just go back to the original deal.
我们可以一起经营
We can run it together.
需要帮忙吗
You need anything?
要是没有我就走了
'cause otherwise I'm gonna head out.
去和助理们喝庆功酒吗
Celebratory drinks with the associates?
是啊
Yep.
你有什么可庆祝的
And what exactly are you celebrating?
不用跟我说什么你很失望  哈维
You know what? You can save the disappointment, Harvey.
-我知道我做了什么  -是吗
- I know what I did. - Do you?
我看到的是你退缩了
Because what I saw is that you backed off
因为你担心伤害你女朋友的感情
because you were worried about hurting your girlfriend's feelings.
这只是一场模拟庭审
It was a fake trial.
对吧  我斟酌了利弊
All right? I weighed the pros and the cons,
觉得为了结果而伤害别人不值得
and I decided it wasn't worth hurting someone for the result.
结果就是你让公司里的每个合伙人
The result is you just told every partner in this firm,
包括我  都知道你是个草包
including myself, that you have a weak stomach,
你没胆子  狠不下心
that you don't have what it takes.
你一直告诉我  我必须选择
You know, you keep telling me that I have to decide
要成为一个怎样的律师
what kind of lawyer I wanna be.
如果我够聪明  大概会成为你这样的律师
And if I were smart, I'd probably be just like you,
因为每个人都知道你是最棒的
because everybody knows you're the best.
但我同样要决定我要成为一个怎样的人
But I'm also trying to decide what kind of person I wanna be.
有时候  相比较你那类人
And sometimes I like my kind of person
我还是更喜欢我这样的
a lot more than yours.
你想知道我是个怎样的人吗
You wanna know what kind of person I am?
心狠手辣但是讲究公平
Tough but fair.
我只说我所看到的
I call it like I see it.
我看到的是一个孩子渴求一个机会
And what I see is a kid who asked for an opportunity
却还不确定  这是不是他想要的
who still hasn't decided if he wants it or not.
来一杯纯麦威士忌
Single malt, please.
怎么来哈佛俱乐部了  我以为你讨厌这地方
Harvard Club? I thought you hate this place.
维加把我从他的酒店赶出来了
Vega kicked me out of his hotel,
你知道的  给人打工...
so, you know, beggars...
别装委屈了
Save the pout.
你当过《法律评论》的头儿
You were head of Law Review,
你是高法法官的书记员
you clerked for a Supreme Court judge,
而且几乎把我打败了
and you almost beat me.
我觉得为这个得喝一杯
I think that deserves a drink.
你请客
On you.
我想高兴点儿  但是我刚被炒鱿鱼了
I'd laugh, but I just got fired.
被事务所解雇了吗
From the firm?
不是
No.
但事务所那边肯定不会满意
But the firm's not going to be happy,
所以我还不想回去
And that's why I'm not already on a plane.
我认识的斯科特可要比这坚强得多
Hey, the Scottie I know is tougher than that.
是吗
Is she?
你想重回母校
Well, you wanna go back to our alma mater
听一场为何女性在科学方面更出色的讲座吗
and see a lecture on why women are better at science?
可能会让你振作起来
Might cheer you up.
可能吧  但我不会和你一起去了
Maybe, but I'm not going with you.
别这样  我们还是朋友  不是吗
Come on, we're still friends, aren't we?
我要结婚了  哈维
I'm getting married, Harvey.
未婚夫叫斯蒂夫
His name is Steve, and, uh,
一个月前他向我求了婚
he asked me a month ago, and, um,
等我回到伦敦
when I get back to London I'm--
我要答应他了
I'm going to say yes.
你想要我说什么
What would you like me to say?
什么也别说了
Nothing.
过来
Come here.
很抱歉我赢了
I'm sorry I won.
不  哈维
No, Harvey...
我讨厌你为了这个说抱歉
I would hate it if you were sorry about that.
你没必要这么做
You didn't have to do that, you know.
-我知道  -我本可以承受的
- I know. - I could've handled it.
-我知道  -你可能没听出来
- I know. - That was a thank-you,
我是在说谢谢
If you couldn't tell.
我明白
I could tell.
珍妮是个不错的证人
So, um, Jenny was a great witness.
既可爱又漂亮
Really likeable and pretty.
是的  是啊
Yeah. Yeah, she is.
我知道这周我对你态度不好
I know I was hard on you this week.
-没事  -不是
- It's okay-- - No, it--
你有没有想过
Did you ever take a minute to wonder
我为什么这么生你的气
why I was so mad at you?
我对你的期待比对大多数人都高
I just expect more from you than most people.
为什么
Why?
你是个聪明人
You're a smart guy.
你会想明白的
You can figure it out.